<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rate on feroxbuster</title><link>/feroxbuster-docs/tags/rate/</link><description>Recent content in Rate on feroxbuster</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/feroxbuster-docs/tags/rate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rate Limiting</title><link>/feroxbuster-docs/docs/examples/rate-limit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/feroxbuster-docs/docs/examples/rate-limit/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="limit-number-of-requests-per-second"&gt;Limit Number of Requests per Second&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert"&gt;
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading"&gt;Note&lt;/h4&gt;

 Rate limiting is enforced on a &lt;strong&gt;per-directory&lt;/strong&gt; basis.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 2.0.0 added the ability to limit the number of requests per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="interaction-with-auto-tune"&gt;Interaction with Auto-Tune&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of version 2.13.1, &lt;code&gt;--rate-limit&lt;/code&gt; can be used together with &lt;code&gt;--auto-tune&lt;/code&gt;. When both flags are provided:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--rate-limit&lt;/code&gt; serves as a &lt;strong&gt;hard cap&lt;/strong&gt; on the maximum request rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--auto-tune&lt;/code&gt; will dynamically adjust the rate limit downward when errors occur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-tune adjustments will &lt;strong&gt;never exceed&lt;/strong&gt; the value specified by &lt;code&gt;--rate-limit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When auto-tune attempts to remove the rate limit (after successful recovery), it will instead reset to the &lt;code&gt;--rate-limit&lt;/code&gt; cap rather than removing it entirely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This combination is useful when you want adaptive rate limiting with a guaranteed maximum to ensure you never exceed a specific request rate.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Auto-tune / Auto-bail</title><link>/feroxbuster-docs/docs/examples/auto-tune/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/feroxbuster-docs/docs/examples/auto-tune/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="auto-tune-or-auto-bail-from-scans"&gt;Auto-tune or Auto-bail from scans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 2.1.0 introduces the &lt;code&gt;--auto-tune&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--auto-bail&lt;/code&gt; flags. You can think of these flags as Policies. Both actions (tuning and bailing) are triggered by the same criteria (below). Policies are only enforced after at least 50 requests have been made (or # of threads, if that&amp;rsquo;s &amp;gt; 50).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policy Enforcement Criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;number of general errors (timeouts, etc) is higher than half the number of threads (or at least 25 if threads are lower) (per directory scanned)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;90% of responses are &lt;code&gt;403|Forbidden&lt;/code&gt; (per directory scanned)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30% of requests are &lt;code&gt;429|Too Many Requests&lt;/code&gt; (per directory scanned)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;both demo gifs below use &amp;ndash;timeout to overload a single-threaded python web server and elicit timeouts&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Threads and Connection Limits</title><link>/feroxbuster-docs/docs/configuration/limit-connections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/feroxbuster-docs/docs/configuration/limit-connections/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-high-level-overview"&gt;A High-Level Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains how the &lt;code&gt;-t&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-L&lt;/code&gt; options work together to determine the overall aggressiveness of a scan. The
combination of the two values set by these options determines how hard your target will get hit and to some extent also
determines how many resources will be consumed on your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-note-on-green-threads"&gt;A Note on Green Threads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;feroxbuster&lt;/code&gt; uses so-called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green_threads"&gt;green threads&lt;/a&gt; as opposed to traditional
kernel/OS threads. This means (at a high-level) that the threads are implemented entirely in userspace, within a single
running process. As a result, a scan with 30 green threads will appear to the OS to be a single process with no
additional light-weight processes associated with it as far as the kernel is concerned. As such, there will not be any
impact to process (&lt;code&gt;nproc&lt;/code&gt;) limits when specifying larger values for &lt;code&gt;-t&lt;/code&gt;. However, these threads will still consume
file descriptors, so you will need to ensure that you have a suitable &lt;code&gt;nlimit&lt;/code&gt; set when scaling up the amount of
threads. More detailed documentation on setting appropriate &lt;code&gt;nlimit&lt;/code&gt; values can be found in
the &lt;a href="../../faq/no-file-descriptors/"&gt;No File Descriptors Available&lt;/a&gt; section of the FAQ&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>